ILGWU. New York Cloak Joint Board records 5780/020
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I: New York Cloak Joint Board Subject Files, 1926-1973
  - Robinson, Dwight Edwards [folder 2 of 2], 1947 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Rutgers Seminar, 1967-1972 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Manuals for Cloak-Out-of-Town Leadership Training Institute, corres.
  - Rocker, Rudolph, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Fund raising; I.c.w. William Green re visa.
  - S, 1941-1965 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Schlesinger, Abraham, 1945-1952 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Schlesinger, Schlesinger and Schlesinger, 1962-1967 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Schlesinger and Bloom, 1952-1961 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Legal matters, Incl. Corres. re Retirement Fund and collective agreements, legal briefs.
  - Schlesinger and Bloom, 1945-1951 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Proposed agreement bet. Investment Comm. of Retirement Fund & Chemical Bank & Trust Co. (1951); Emil Schlesinger speech on the "labor problem" (1947
  - Schlesinger and Bloom, 1941-1944 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Incl. memo to National Labor Relations Board re Cloak Jt. Bd. vs Fred P. Weissmann, Inc. (1940); Emil Schlesinger speech on anniversary of 1910 strike (1943).
  - Schlesinger and Bloom, 1938-1940 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Incl. "Memorandum of the Joint Board of Dress and Waistmakers' Union of Greater N.Y., submitted to the Interstate Commerce Commission." (c. 1940)
  - Section Work Department, Cloak Jt. Bd. [folder 1 of 2], 1951-1961 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Departmental reports from Silvestro Ozzi & Paul Device.
  - Section Work Department, Cloak Jt. Bd. [folder 2 of 2], 1951-1961 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Semi-Annual Work Bonus, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Memorandum re approval of Union benefit by State Labor Commissioner in Connecticut; rules & regulations.
  - Seminar, Unity House, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    Corres., program, photograph.
  - Shop Chairmen, 1943-1965 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    Meetings, speeches & form ltrs.; response from legislators to resolution for $1 minimum wage (1960).
  - Social-Democratic Federation, 1940-1953 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Incl. speech by I. Nagler, "The Results of the Recent Election" (1952).
  - Socialist Party U.S.A. and, Social-Democrats U.S.A., 1947-1973 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    Incl. Norman Thomas ltrs.
  - Student, B. A., 1940-1941 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Case, statements, transcript of hearings, decision.
  - Study of Population Characteristics and Hospitalization Experience, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Locals 23-25 & 62 Welfare Fund Study by M.A. Morehead & Rose S. Donaldson; also incl. memo, "Program Planning for Health Care, " Columbia University School of Public Health & Administrative Medicine.
  - T, 1962-1970 (Box 37, Folder 3a)
  - Taft-Hartley Bill, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 3b)
    Statements and speeches in opposition to bill.
  - Training Institute, ILGWU, 1950-1964 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Trucking Association, Inc., New York and Brooklyn Cloak and Suit [folder 1 of 2], 1939-1955 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    I.c.w. Harry Klar & Harry Chancer; also incl. decisions of impartial chairman.
  - Trucking Association, Inc., New York and Brooklyn Cloak and Suit [folder 2 of 2], 1939-1955 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - U-V, 1940-1978 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    Incl. speech by Louis Stulberg to United Hebrew Trades, Umhey ltr. re Roosevelt birthday fund appeal.
  - Uniform Industrial Control Committee, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    "Plan on Uniform Industrial Control, " submitted by J. Breslaw (chairman) and "Discussion on Uniform Industrial Control."
  - Union Health Center, NYC, 1960-1971 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    Incl. Leo Price ltr. (1960) re retirement.
  - Union Vanguard, 1938 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    Translations of articles on Union.
  - Unions, 1946-1973 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Incl. Corres. re Union contribution to ACWA Farah Strike.
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1949-1958 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Unser Stimme, 1966-1972 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    (Notre Voix)
  - Violations, 1943-1970 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Investigations and reports; incl. Verna Fashions & Elco Coat Co. report (1969-70).
  - W, 1969-1971 (Box 38, Folder 4a)
  - Workers Benefit Committee, GEB, 1965-1973 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    (Health & Welfare Committee 1965 and before) Agendas.
  - Weizman Institute of Science, Israel, 1949-1950 (Box 38, Folder 5b)
    American Committee for the Weizman Institute of Science fund raising.
  - Workers Defense League, 1949-1972 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Incl. form ltrs. of Cloakmakers Branch, fund raising.
  - Workmen's Circle, 1940-1970 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Corres., speeches & statements.
  - World Rehabilitation Fund, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    I.c.w. Howard Rusk.
  - X-Y-Z, 1958-1973 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Yiddish Encyclopaedia, 1948-1950 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - YIVO Institute for Social Research [folder 1 of 2], 1949-1972 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    I.c.w. Samuel Lapin, Max Weinreich; corres. & memos re Jewish Labor Movement History.
  - YIVO Institute for Social Research [folder 2 of 2], 1949-1972 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Young People's Socialist League, 1968-1973 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Zukunft, 1948-1972 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    Corres., article by H. Mendelsund (1960).
  - Zygelboim (Artur) Monument (NYC), 1963-1965 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    Corres. re erecting monument and copy of D.D. ltr. to Robert F. Wagner criticizing New York City Art Commission for denying authorization to erect monument (Feb. 1965).
  - Grievance Committee, Cloak Jt. Bd., 1958-1959 (Box 39, Folder all)
    Cases #2687-2711; members' violations of Union rules.
  - Grievance Committee, Cloak Jt. Bd., 1959-1960 (Box 40, Folder all)
    Cases #2712-2736; members' violations of Union rules.
  - Grievance Committee, Cloak Jt. Bd., 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder all)
    Cases #2377-2769; members' violations of Union rules.
  - Grievance Committee, Cloak Jt. Bd., 1961-1962 (Box 42, Folder all)
    Cases #2770-2801; members' violations of Union rules.
  - Grievance Committee, Cloak Jt. Bd., 1962-1963 (Box 43, Folder all)
    Cases #2802-2839; members' violations of Union rules.
- Series II: Cloak-Out-Of-Town Department Files, 1926-1971
  - Adopted children, 1951 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Celebrations, Christmas, 1961-1971 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Cloak Out-of Town Department, 1957-1964 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Newspapers and staff memos.
  - Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1926-1960 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Historic information, newspaper clippings.
  - Conventions, ILGWU, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Elections.
  - Conventions, ILGWU, 1962-1965 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Resolutions and notes.
  - Education Department, COT, 1952-1971 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Education Department, COT, 1962-1968 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Joint Council of Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1960-1964 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Joint Council, COT, 1965-1971 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Leaflets (n.d.) (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Local 36-39 (Yonkers), 1960-1965 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Local 129 (Jamaica, L.I.,N.Y.), 1964-1971 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Local 130 (Monmouth County, N.Y. ), 1951-1969 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    Incl. executive board minutes, 1951-52.
  - Local 133 (Union City, N.J.), 1968 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Local 134 (Paterson, N.J.), 1968 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Local 141-147 (Bridgeport, Conn.), 1968-1970 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    Local 158 (Passaic, N.J.), 1965. Local 165 (Newburgh, N.Y.), 1962
  - Locals, 1952-1960 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    Newspaper clippings and data.
  - New Jersey Political Action Conference, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - New York Cloak Joint Board, 1951-1962 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    Notes of meeting, 1962; information re. section work and designation of contractors.
  - Organizing, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    Leaflets.
  - Photographs. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Politics, 1960-1969 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    Corres, and press releases.
  - Politics, 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    COT Citizenship Committees (CCC).
  - Politics, 1960-1969 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    Leaflets, newspaper clippings.
  - Politics, 1960-1966 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    Letters to legislators.
  - Publicity, 1953-1962 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Racketeers, 1950-1958 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Leaflets and newspaper clippings.
  - Retirement, 1953-1971 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    Activities and lists of names of retirees.
  - Rubin, George, 1950-1960 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Rutgers Seminar, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Manual for COT Leadership Training Institute; corres.
  - Rutgers Seminar, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    Members' applications.
  - Rutgers Seminar, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    Post-seminar evaluations.
  - Rutgers Seminar, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Scholarship Program, 1968-1971 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Shop Chairmen [folder 1 of 2], 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    Corres.; lists of shop chairmen and executive board members..
  - Shop Chairmen [folder 2 of 2], 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Staff Meeting Reports, 1958-1965 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Union Health Center, Newark, 1951-1942 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    Minutes of Board of Directors.
  - Union Label Department, ILGWU, 1960-1962 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Union Label Department, ILGWU, 1960-1963 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Union Leadership Classes, 1962 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    Institute of Labor Management Relations at Rutgers University.
  - University of Connecticut Labor Education Center Conference, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    Corres.; program; printed material.